我们将首先重新介绍二维几何的基本原理。首先，
We’ll start by recapping some fundamentals of two-dimensional geometry. To start with,
我们要谈谈欧几里得飞机。欧几里德平面是非曲面
we’re going to talk about a Euclidian plane. A Euclidian plane is a non-curved surface
欧几里德几何规则适用的地方。我们通常认为这是理所当然的。
where the rules of Euclidian geometry apply. We normally take this for granted.
我们只是明确指出我们正在使用平面。
We’re just going to be explicit about the fact that we’re working with flat surfaces.
第二个概念是笛卡尔坐标。同样，这是一个你应该很好的概念
The second concept is Cartesian coordinates. Again, this is a concept you should be well
熟悉。我们有一组正交轴，通常标记为X和Y.我们有一个
familiar with. We have a set of orthogonal axes typically labeled X and Y. We have a
点P，我们根据距离描述其相对于原点的位置
point P and we describe its position with respect to the origin in terms of distances
沿X和Y轴。对您来说可能不太熟悉的概念将是同质的
along the X and Y axes. A concept that is perhaps less familiar to you will be homogenous
坐标，我们将在本讲座中大量使用它们。那些你的人
coordinates and we’re going to be using them a lot in this lecture. Those of you who’ve
完成了机器人课程的介绍，已经遇到了同质的坐标。
done the introduction to robotics course will have already encountered homogenous coordinates.
为了表示二维笛卡尔空间中的一个点，我们用一对来描述它
To represent a point in a two-dimensional Cartesian space, we describe it by a pair
作为元组X，Y写的数字，我们说这一点存在于二维空间中
of numbers written as tuple X, Y and we say that this point lives in the space of two-dimensional
实数，我们用符号R2（R平方）表示。
real numbers, which we denote by the symbol R2 (R squared).
在同质坐标中，我们用三个数字表示相同的点。在这种情况下，
In homogenous coordinates, we represent the same point with three numbers. In this case,
我们把它表示为X，Y和头号。事实上，头号有些武断;
we’ve represent it as X, Y and the number one. In fact, the number one is somewhat arbitrary;
它可以是任何非零常数。我们现在说这一点属于二维的
it could be any non-zero constant. We say now that this point belongs to the two-dimensional
投影空间，我们用符号P2（P平方）表示。所以这是同一点，
projective space, which we denote by the symbol P2 (P squared). So it’s the same point,
只有两种不同的方式来表示它。同质表示，表示
just two different ways to represent it. The homogenous representation, the representation
在这个讲座中，投射空间对我们来说非常非常方便。
in projective space is going to be very, very handy to us in this lecture.
现在要从同质坐标转换为笛卡尔坐标，我要去
Now to convert from homogenous coordinate to a Cartesian coordinate, I’m going to
从这里表示为Xtilde，Ytilde和Ztilde的非常一般的同质坐标开始。
start with the very general homogenous coordinate denoted here as X tilde, Y tilde and Z tilde.
要通过笛卡尔坐标转换它，我所做的就是取前两个数字和
To convert it through a Cartesian coordinate what I do is take the first two numbers and
除以第三个。因此X和Y笛卡尔坐标由Z波浪号上的X波浪号给出
divide by the third. So X and Y Cartesian coordinates are given by X tilde on Z tilde
和Y代表Ztilde。
and Y tilde on Z tilde respectively.
现在一位数学家会说，在投射空间中，线和点有双重性。他们有
Now a mathematician would say that in projective space, lines and points have duals. They have
等价的陈述。一些非常有趣和非常有用的东西来自这种二元性。
equivalent representations. Some very interesting and very useful things flow from this duality.
我们可以用同质的形式写一条与我们习惯的有点不同的线
We can write a line in homogenous form a little bit different to what we’re used to but
我们可以写一条线作为三个数字，在这里表示为L1，L2和L3。想象一下，我
we can write a line as three numbers denoted here as L1, L2 and L3. Imagine that I’ve
得到一个沿着那条线移动的点。所以这条线实际上是所有可能的集合
got a point which moves along that line. So the line is really the set of all possible
沿着它的点。我可以表达这样一个事实，即关键点在于
points that lie along it. I can express the fact that the point lies on the line by the
线的点积和点等​​于零。我们将此称为重点
dot product of the line and the point being equal to zero. We refer to this as the point
一条线的方程。根据可能存在的所有点来定义一条线
equation of a line. A line is defined in terms of all the points that could possibly lie
沿着它。
along it.
现在我可以扩展它，我们可以看到它看起来与传统的有点不同
Now I can expand that out and we can see that that looks a little bit different to the conventional
直线的笛卡尔表示。但是如果我们从同质坐标进行转换
Cartesian representation of a line. But if we do the transformation from homogenous coordinates
对于笛卡尔坐标，我们可以证明线的这两个表示是等价的。
to Cartesian coordinates, we can show that these two representations of a line are equivalent.
使用同质形式的一个优点是它很容易表示一条线
An advantage of using the homogenous form is that it’s very easy to represent a line
这是垂直的，在笛卡尔坐标系中，这意味着线的梯度是
that is vertical where in Cartesian coordinates, that means that the gradient of the line is
等于无穷大。在同质形式下，我们非常简单方便地对待这种情况。
equal to infinity. In homogenous form, we treat that situation very simply and conveniently.
我们不需要引入任何无穷大。我们也可能对如何描述感兴趣
We don’t need to introduce any infinities. We also might be interested in how to describe
一条连接两点的线。所以这里我们有两个点，这是一条经过的线
a line that joins two points. So here we have two points and here’s a line that passes
通过这两点。然后记住的线的同质表示
through those two points. Then the homogenous representation of the line which remember
是三个向量简单地由两个点的交叉积给出
is the three vector is given simply by the cross-product of the two points that lie on
这条线。这是一种非常非常简单的方法，可以找到连接两点的线的方程
the line. So a very, very simple way of finding the equation of a line that joins two points
比笛卡尔坐标更方便。
much, much more conveniently than it is for Cartesian coordinates.
我们可能也对交叉点的坐标问题感兴趣
We might also be interested in the problem of the coordinate of the point at the intersection
两行。所以这里我们有两条线，这是交叉点和交叉点
of two lines. So here we have two lines and this is the intersection point and the intersection
点由两条线的交叉积给出。我们称之为线方程
point is given by the cross-product of the two lines. We call this the line equation
一点。该点由两行定义。
of a point. The point is defined in terms of two lines.
所以让我们创造一个观点。水平坐标为100.垂直坐标为200.和点
So let’s create a point. A horizontal coordinate of 100. A vertical coordinate of 200. And points
表示为列向量。那是我在那里写的行向量，
are represented as column vectors. So that’s a row vector that I’ve written just there,
所以我会调换它。这样就会显示为列向量。所以这是欧几里德
so I will transpose it. So that will display as a column vector. So this is a Euclidean
或点的笛卡尔坐标。
or Cartesian coordinate for a point.
现在我们可以使用函数将欧几里德坐标转换为齐次坐标
Now we can convert the Euclidean coordinate into a homogeneous coordinate using the function
e2h，我们可以看到它所做的一切都附加了1。所以现在而不是矢量
e2h, and we can see that all it has done is appended a 1 to it. So now instead of a vector
有两个元素，它现在是一个有三个元素的列向量。最后一个元素是
with two elements, its now a column vector with three elements. The last element is a
一。
one.
现在我们可以使用。将齐次坐标转换回欧几里德坐标
Now we can convert the homogeneous coordinate back to a Euclidean coordinate by using the
反函数h2e，对于齐次到欧几里德，我将其应用于答案
inverse function h2e, for homogeneous to Euclidean, and I apply that to the answer
对于最后一个操作，我们看到它现在回到了一个带有两个元素的向量。
for the last operation and we see that it is back now to a vector with two elements.
结果是我们开始使用的向量。
The result is the vector that we started with.